<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Use Case on drasyl provides secure, software-defined overlay networks, connecting all your devices</title><link>https://drasyl.org/tags/use-case/</link><description>Recent content in Use Case on drasyl provides secure, software-defined overlay networks, connecting all your devices</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 23:44:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drasyl.org/tags/use-case/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>drasyl: From Peer-to-Peer Library to Software-Defined Networking Platform</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/from-p2p-to-sdn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 23:44:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/from-p2p-to-sdn/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/suzanne-d-williams-VMKBFR6r_jg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Feet dangling from a building">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="origins-and-motivation">Origins and Motivation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-1-0-released/">Five years ago&lt;/a>, our work on drasyl began within the &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20231201155219/https://sane.city/">SANE research project&lt;/a>, which aimed to enable decentralized, secure, and privacy-preserving data sharing between citizens and institutions. Achieving this required direct, efficient, and secure communication, even across communication barriers prevalent on the Internet such as NATs, firewalls, and IPv4/IPv6 incompatibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Established solutions like WebRTC, while functional, rely on layered protocol stacks (STUN, TURN, SIP, DTLS) that add infrastructure dependencies, complex handshake procedures, multiple points of failure, and increased connection latency. These characteristics did not align with our architectural and operational requirements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software-Defined Overlay Networking for the Deployment of Distributed Applications at the Edge</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-dissertation-published/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:33:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-dissertation-published/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/suad-kamardeen-ItFTJoh1A8c-unsplash.jpg" alt="Black pendant lamp photo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are pleased to announce that Heiko Bornholdt&amp;rsquo;s dissertation, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Software-Defined Overlay Networking for the Deployment of Distributed Applications at the Edge&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>, has been published.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This doctoral dissertation introduces drasyl and its foundational concept of software-defined overlay networks. drasyl was developed as part of this dissertation—or, as some might say, the dissertation was developed around drasyl!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Outdoor Navigation for Wheelchair Users</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/wheelchair-navigation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/wheelchair-navigation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/nayeli-dalton-GIJWGUXKEzY-unsplash.jpg" alt="woman in wheelchair">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s post is about the just finished &lt;a href="https://www.inf.uni-hamburg.de/en/inst/ab/dos/teaching.html#27562742">master project lecture about smart cities&lt;/a> at Universität Hamburg.
The project&amp;rsquo;s goal was the prototypical implementation of a navigation solution for wheelchair users.
For this purpose, a suitable route was selected with a wheelchair-friendly surface.
The data required for navigation is automatically collected by a sensor box that can be attached to wheelchairs.
This data is exchanged from wheelchair user to wheelchair user with the help of drasyl.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Distributed Key-Value Stores Built with drasyl</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/distributed-key-value-store/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/distributed-key-value-store/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/chris-montgomery-smgTvepind4-unsplash.jpg" alt="macbook pro displaying group of people">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post presents another use case of drasyl:
During an &lt;a href="https://vsis-www.informatik.uni-hamburg.de/vsis/teaching/coursekvv/528">eight-day block course at the university&lt;/a>, a total of five student groups designed and prototyped key-value stores.
In the process, drasyl was used for communication so that the students could fully concentrate on implementing the business logic of the key-value store.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bringing Computation Offloading to the Edge</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/edge-computing-thesis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 15:06:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/edge-computing-thesis/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/jake-ingle-s-t1oJXKYI4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Feet dangling from a building">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s post is about the master thesis &amp;ldquo;A Secure Context-Aware Middleware for Computation Offloading in Untrustworthy, Open, and Dynamic Edge Environments&amp;rdquo; by Kevin Röbert.
In his master&amp;rsquo;s thesis, Kevin Röbert designed, implemented, and evaluated a system capable of offloading computations to the cloud, grid, and edge devices.
He integrated drasyl into the &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;q=tasklet+system">Tasklet&lt;/a> computation offloading middleware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accessing Smart City Services in Untrustworthy Environments via Decentralized Privacy-Preserving Overlay Networks</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/smart-city-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/smart-city-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/denys-nevozhai-_QoAuZGAoPY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Cityscape and interchange">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce that our paper &amp;ldquo;Accessing Smart City Services in Untrustworthy Environments via Decentralized Privacy-Preserving Overlay Networks&amp;rdquo; has been published in the proceedings of the 2021 IEEE International Conference on Service-Oriented System Engineering (SOSE)&amp;quot;.
Within this paper, we presented how our approach can be used to provide the foundations for a network of Smart City Services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smart Urban Data Space for Citizen Science</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/sane/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/sane/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/sane_logo.png" alt="SANE logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today we are talking about another use case for drasyl: &lt;a href="https://sane.city">SANE&lt;/a>. This use case is special for us because it finally made us decide to develop drasyl. The SANE project is now finished; therefore, we would like to present the project&amp;rsquo;s results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Integrity in Smart Urban Data Spaces</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/data-aggregation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/data-aggregation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/pietro-jeng-n6B49lTx7NM-unsplash.jpg" alt="green and red light illuminated net">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s paper is about a master thesis that deals with in-network data processing systems.
Maintaining data integrity in in-network data processing systems is difficult.
While individual nodes can be assumed to cooperate in closed systems, malicious participants must be detected and dealt with in open networks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SkABNet: A Attribut-Based SkipNet built on drasyl</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/skabnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/skabnet/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/skabnet_logo.png" alt="SkABNet logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today we would like to present you another use case of drasyl: A colleague of ours developed a distributed data structure based on the &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/tr-2002-92.pdf">SkipNet&lt;/a> presented by Microsoft. In addition to that, he added capabilities to store multi-attributed data on a SkipNet.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>