<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on drasyl is a high-performance framework for rapid development of distributed applications</title><link>https://drasyl.org/tags/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on drasyl is a high-performance framework for rapid development of distributed applications</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 15:06:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drasyl.org/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bringing Computation Offloading to the Edge</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/edge-computing-thesis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 15:06:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/edge-computing-thesis/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/jake-ingle-s-t1oJXKYI4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Feet dangling from a building">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s post is about the master thesis &amp;ldquo;A Secure Context-Aware Middleware for Computation Offloading in Untrustworthy, Open, and Dynamic Edge Environments&amp;rdquo; by Kevin Röbert.
In his master&amp;rsquo;s thesis, Kevin Röbert designed, implemented, and evaluated a system capable of offloading computations to the cloud, grid, and edge devices.
He integrated drasyl into the &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;q=tasklet+system">Tasklet&lt;/a> computation offloading middleware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accessing Smart City Services in Untrustworthy Environments via Decentralized Privacy-Preserving Overlay Networks</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/smart-city-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/smart-city-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/denys-nevozhai-_QoAuZGAoPY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Cityscape and interchange">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce that our paper &amp;ldquo;Accessing Smart City Services in Untrustworthy Environments via Decentralized Privacy-Preserving Overlay Networks&amp;rdquo; has been published in the proceedings of the 2021 IEEE International Conference on Service-Oriented System Engineering (SOSE)&amp;quot;.
Within this paper, we presented how our approach can be used to provide the foundations for a network of Smart City Services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smart Urban Data Space for Citizen Science</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/sane/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/sane/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/sane_logo.png" alt="SANE logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today we are talking about another use case for drasyl: &lt;a href="https://sane.city">SANE&lt;/a>. This use case is special for us because it finally made us decide to develop drasyl. The SANE project is now finished; therefore, we would like to present the project&amp;rsquo;s results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Integrity in Smart Urban Data Spaces</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/data-aggregation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/data-aggregation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/pietro-jeng-n6B49lTx7NM-unsplash.jpg" alt="green and red light illuminated net">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s paper is about a master thesis that deals with in-network data processing systems.
Maintaining data integrity in in-network data processing systems is difficult.
While individual nodes can be assumed to cooperate in closed systems, malicious participants must be detected and dealt with in open networks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SkABNet: A Attribut-Based SkipNet built on drasyl</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/skabnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/skabnet/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/skabnet_logo.png" alt="SkABNet logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today we would like to present you another use case of drasyl: A colleague of ours developed a distributed data structure based on the &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/tr-2002-92.pdf">SkipNet&lt;/a> presented by Microsoft. In addition to that, he added capabilities to store multi-attributed data on a SkipNet.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>