<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publication on drasyl provides secure, software-defined overlay networks, connecting all your devices</title><link>https://drasyl.org/tags/publication/</link><description>Recent content in Publication on drasyl provides secure, software-defined overlay networks, connecting all your devices</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drasyl.org/tags/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simplifying Distributed Application Deployment at the Edge through Software-Defined Overlay Networks</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/simplifying_distributed_apps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/simplifying_distributed_apps/</guid><description>&lt;p>Deploying distributed applications at the edge is challenging: devices are heterogeneous, network conditions change dynamically, and resources are often limited. In our latest publication, we show how &lt;strong>software-defined overlay networks&lt;/strong> can simplify deployments and reduce complexity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software-Defined Overlay Networking for the Deployment of Distributed Applications at the Edge</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-dissertation-published/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:33:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-dissertation-published/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are pleased to announce that Heiko Bornholdt&amp;rsquo;s dissertation, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Software-Defined Overlay Networking for the Deployment of Distributed Applications at the Edge&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>, has been published.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This doctoral dissertation introduces drasyl and its foundational concept of software-defined overlay networks. drasyl was developed as part of this dissertation—or, as some might say, the dissertation was developed around drasyl!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accessing Smart City Services in Untrustworthy Environments via Decentralized Privacy-Preserving Overlay Networks</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/smart-city-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/smart-city-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce that our paper &amp;ldquo;Accessing Smart City Services in Untrustworthy Environments via Decentralized Privacy-Preserving Overlay Networks&amp;rdquo; has been published in the proceedings of the 2021 IEEE International Conference on Service-Oriented System Engineering (SOSE)&amp;quot;.
Within this paper, we presented how our approach can be used to provide the foundations for a network of Smart City Services.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>