<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Releases on drasyl provides secure, software-defined overlay networks, connecting all your devices</title><link>https://drasyl.org/tags/releases/</link><description>Recent content in Releases on drasyl provides secure, software-defined overlay networks, connecting all your devices</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 21:25:26 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drasyl.org/tags/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Announcing drasyl 0.12.0: A New Core, Rewritten in Rust</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-12-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 21:25:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-12-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/derailed-drips-Q5cT8yw7V3Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are excited to announce the release of &lt;strong>drasyl 0.12.0&lt;/strong>. In addition to several bug fixes and dependency updates, this version brings a fundamental transformation:
&lt;strong>The core of the drasyl peer-to-peer network has been completely re-engineered.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.11.0 released with performance improvements, fixes, and dynamic overlay constructon</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-11-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 19:21:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-11-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/anton-filatov-O_5SJuSOxZA-unsplash.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.11.0.
This maintenance release brings performance improvements, fixes and the new CLI sub-command &lt;code>sdon&lt;/code> for the creation of dynamic overlays.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.10.0 released with performance improvements, fixes, and globally distributed super peers</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-10-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 20:27:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-10-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.10.0.
This maintenance release brings performance improvements and a new set of globally distributed super peers resulting in faster peer discovery, connection establishments, and traffic relaying performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.9.0 released with C and Python Bindings and support for Publish/Subscribe Messaging, Remote Message Invocation, and more!</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-9-0-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 11:34:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-9-0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/pexels-alexander-grey-1148496.jpg" alt="Assorted color bricks">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.9.0.
This release will bring drasyl natively to C and Python!
In addition, drasyl now ships with optional components allowing you to utilize the publish/subscribe messaging pattern, remote message invocation, decentralized membership management, and a distributed lookup service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.8.0 released with improved Hole Punching, Remote Controlling for CLI, and increased TUN Device performance</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-8-0-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 12:14:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-8-0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/jack-anstey-zS4lUqLEiNA-unsplash.jpg" alt="aerial photography of road">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.8.0 with improved hole punching protocol, remote controlling via JSON-RPC for &lt;code>node&lt;/code> and &lt;code>tun&lt;/code> CLI commands, and increased TUN device performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.7.0 released with TUN Device Support and Faster UDP Hole Punching</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-7-0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:14:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-7-0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/clint-adair-BW0vK-FA3eg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Green rope meshwork">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.7.0 with TUN device support, faster UDP hole punching, IP broadcast-based peer discovery, and identity generation utility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.6.0 released with Support for Netty Handlers, Backpressure Mechanism, and Tunnel Utility</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-6-0-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 01:57:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-6-0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/pexels-pixabay-210008.jpg" alt="Grayscale photograph of an empty tunnel">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.6.0 with support for &lt;a href="https://netty.io">Netty&lt;/a> channel handlers, backpressure mechanism, option to disable data plane encryption, file transfer for wormhole utility, and port tunneling utility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.5.0 released with E2E Encryption, LAN Discovery, and TCP Fallback</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-5-0-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 23:39:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-5-0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/pexels-life-of-pix-4291.jpg" alt="Brass Color Metal Padlock With Chain">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.5.0 with end-to-end encryption, an IP multicast-based peer discovery, and TCP-fallback if UDP is blocked.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.4.0 released with UDP Hole Punching, Message Chunking, and Bandwidth Measurement Utility</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-4-0-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 22:13:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-4-0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/dan-burton-nRW4I8kuyd8-unsplash.jpg" alt="person holding fist to camera">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.4.0 with UPD hole punching, message chunking, in-process discovery, static routes, and network bandwidth measurement utility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.3.0 released with Network Separation, and Groups Plugin</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-3-0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 12:43:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-3-0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/andrew-moca-r3Nl1mIKqbI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Hands holding a paper chain">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.3.0 with network separation, groups plugin, and some performance tweaks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.2.0 released with Plugin Support, Message Marshaling, and a Wormhole!</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-2-0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:01:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-2-0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/wormhole-g4db043e5d_1920.jpg" alt="wormhole">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the release of drasyl 0.2.0 with plugin support, message marshaling, port forwarding, a filesystem-based peer discovery, and an ominous wormhole ðŸ•³ï¸.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl goes Maven Central</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-goes-maven-central/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 02:38:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-goes-maven-central/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today we are releasing drasyl 0.1.2.
Apart from some bug fixes, this release comes with a pleasant change: Starting with this version, we&amp;rsquo;re publishing drasyl releases to &lt;a href="https://mvnrepository.com/artifact/org.drasyl/drasyl-core">Maven Central&lt;/a>.
This means adding our Maven repository to &lt;code>pom.xml&lt;/code> is no longer necessary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drasyl 0.1.0 released - The Journey Begins!</title><link>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-1-0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 15:36:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://drasyl.org/blog/drasyl-0-1-0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://drasyl.org/img/matt-duncan-IUY_3DvM__w-unsplash.jpg" alt="Highway 212 forest road">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are excited to announce the very first release of drasyl 0.1.0.
drasyl is an open-source, general-purpose overlay network that is concurrent, resilient, flexible, and automated. It presents itself to the user as a transparent system that offers suitable discovery and awareness methods, mainly focusing on smart city and IoT devices.
Nevertheless, drasyl is not limited to smart city and IoT but is intended for universal use in all decentralized Java-based projects.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>